Welcome to the Sensor Fusion module.
欢迎来到传感器融合模块
Sensor Fusion has a car or any sensing robot for
传感器融合可帮助汽车或任何具备感知功能的机器人
that matter, understand and track its environment.
了解并追踪其所处的环境
&gt;&gt; The environment could consist of other cars, or barriers on the shoulder
- 环境中可能有车辆、路肩上的障碍物
of the road, or motorcycles, or pedestrians walking across the road.
摩托车 或穿越道路的行人
&gt;&gt; Don't hit the pedestrians.
- 不要撞到行人
&gt;&gt; That's right, don't hit the pedestrians.
- 没错 不要撞到行人
&gt;&gt; We'll get to that.
- 这是我们的目标。
First, I want you all to meet a few people.
首先 我来介绍一下我们的教师队伍
This is Michael Maile, the Director of the Sensor Fusion Team at Mercedes-Benz.
这是 Michael Maile 梅赛德斯-奔驰的传感器融合团队主管
&gt;&gt; Hello.
- 大家好
&gt;&gt; And also from Mercedes-Benz,
- 此我们还有两名工程师
we're joined by two engineers on Michael's team, Andrei Vatavu.
也来自 Michael Maile 的团队 他们是 Andrei Vatavu
&gt;&gt; Hi.
- 嗨
&gt;&gt; And Dominik Nuss.
- 还有 Dominik Nuss
&gt;&gt; Welcome.
- 大家好
&gt;&gt; By the end of this module, you'll implement your own
- 本模块结束时 你需要实现自己的
sensor fusion algorithm to track a pedestrian relative to a car.
传感器融合算法 用于追踪车辆旁边的行人
To do this you'll need to fuse lidar and radar data.
要做到这一点 你需要将激光雷达和雷达数据相融合
You'll be working with a technique called a Kalman filter.
你需要用到一种工具：卡尔曼滤波器
You'll start with a basic Kalman filter and then Andre and
你首先需要学习基础的卡尔曼滤波器 接下来
Dominic will help you extend it to more complex data.
Andre 和 Dominic 会帮助扩展它以应对更为复杂的数据
&gt;&gt; We're in the first lesson right now, in a moment,
- 现在就是我们的第一堂课 一会儿
Micheal will walk you through the basics of lidar and radar sensors.
Michael 会向大家介绍激光雷达和雷达的基础知识
&gt;&gt; In the second lesson, you'll be with Sebastian.
- 在第二堂课上 你会跟 Sebastian 学习
When it comes to the concept of Kalman filters, he's the best.
他是卡尔曼滤波器概念方面的专家
You'll work through part of Sebastian's AI for robotics course,
他会带你学习一些机器人学课程中的人工智能知识
in which you'll build a simplified Kalman filter in Python.
你需要使用 Python 构建一个简化的卡尔曼滤波器
If you've already taken Sebastian's course, feel free to skip ahead.
如果你已经学过了 Sebastian 的课程 可以跳过这堂课
&gt;&gt; Then we'll come to a big change.
- 接下来 就是挑战时刻了
&gt;&gt; You mean C++?
- 你是说 C++？
&gt;&gt; Indeed.
- 没错
&gt;&gt; Sensor fusion needs to happen quickly,
- 传感器融合必须迅速
which means we need to use a high performance language.
因此 我们需要高性能语言
C++ is a critical language for performing real-time operations.
对于实时计算来讲，C++是一门很关键的语言
We use it as Mercedes and you use it to build your project in this module.
在梅赛德斯我们大量使用这门语言 在本课程中 你也要使用它来完成自己的项目
&gt;&gt; So the third lesson is what are calling a C++ checkpoint.
- 因此 第三课我们叫做 C++ 知识点检查
You'll face some challenges that test your ability to apply C++ techniques.
你要解决一些难题 测试你应用 C++ 的能力
Once you complete them, you're ready to build basic Kalman filters with C++.
完成这些题目后 你就可以开始使用 C++ 创建基础的卡尔曼滤波器了
&gt;&gt; So, what if you don't already know C++?
- 但是 如果你真的不了解 C++ 呢？
In that case,
如果是这样的话，
we've provided some resources that can help you get up to speed.
我们提供了一些资源 可以帮助你跟上进度
You can use these resources to familiarize yourself with core C++
你可以使用这些资源熟悉核心的 C++ 概念
concepts so that you can pass these challenges.
从而解决这些难题
The good news is that the C++ you'll use in this module
好消息是 你在本模块中使用的 C++
will look quite a bit like Python.
和 Python 非常相似
You should be fine with just the basics of control flow, functions, classes, and
你应该能迅速掌握控制流、函数、类
references.
和引用等基础知识
&gt;&gt; After that you'll be working with Andre and
- 此后 你会跟着 Andre 和
Dominic for the next two lessons.
Dominic 学习后面的两堂课
&gt;&gt; Lidar and radar produce very different data.
- 激光雷达和雷达产生的数据差别很大
I'll help you implement a Kalman filter in C++ to fuse together data from both
我会帮助你使用 C++ 实现一个卡尔曼滤波器
of these sensors.
融合这两种传感器的数据
&gt;&gt; In my lesson, you'll perform sensor fusion with an unscented Kalman filter.
- 在我的课上 你需要使用无损卡尔曼滤波器进行传感器融合
This is a different technique for object tracking that provides another tool for
这和对象追踪的技术不同 它提供了新的工具
handling non linear motion, such as a turning car or a bicycle.
用于处理非线性运动 如汽车或自行车的拐弯
&gt;&gt; Okay, this is going to be fun.
- 好的 听起来很有趣
Let's get started.
我们开始吧
Michael, are you ready to show off your self driving car?
Michael 你准备好炫耀你的无人车了吗？
&gt;&gt; Definitely.
- 当然